Tufts University Development Corporation Records UA147
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University Development Corporation Records
1989 -- 1992
1989 -- 1998
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University Development Coorporation
University Advancement Division
UA147
2.4 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series: Administrative and legal files; Correspondence; Meeting files; and Project files.
Scope and Contents
This collection include meeting minutes, correspondence, planning materials, and subject files related to the Corporation and its plans to construct a multi-purpose medical building on top of South Station in Boston. The bulk of the materials date from the late 1980s and early 1990s. Many subject files specifically address issues related to securing the air rights for the building.
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts Development Corporation is a privately held corporation established to manage Tufts' investments. Established in 1989, the Corporation's main focus has been the construction of a skyscraper on top of South Station in Boston, near the Tufts Boston Campus.
Conditions Governing Access
Records containing information related to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
Finance; Facilities; Legal and Regulatory
- Administrative and legal files, 1989 -- 1995; UA147.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of files which document the incorporation of the Tufts Development Corporation and its legal status. Many files also reference the main project in the Project files: the construction of a building on South Station, Boston.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation.
  - Annual financial reports/Mass. TUDC filings, 1991 -- 1992; UA147.001.001.00001 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Annual report to the Commonwealth of MA, 1995; UA147.001.001.00002 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Bank authorizations/resolutions, 1990; UA147.001.001.00003 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Directors and officers liability insurance, 1990 -- 1993; UA147.001.001.00004 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Drafts of articles of organization and by-laws evidencing changes, 1989; UA147.001.001.00005 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - [Information and mailing list 1 of 2], 1991 -- 1992; UA147.001.001.00006 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Schedule [Information and mailing list 1 of 2], 1991 -- 1992; UA147.001.001.00007 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Information and mailing lists, 1991 -- 1992; UA147.001.001.00008 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - List of directors and officers, 1908 -- 1993; UA147.001.001.00009 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - [Mailing labels], 1989; UA147.001.001.00010 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Massachusetts Biotech Council, 1989; UA147.001.001.00011 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - MBTA Loan Agreement, 1991; UA147.001.001.00012 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Peat Marwick, 1992; UA147.001.001.00013 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Reports of planning meetings pre-dating TUDC incorporation, 1989; UA147.001.001.00014 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
- Correspondence files, 1989 -- 1998; UA147.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains correspondence of members of Tufts Development Corporation and related to Corporation business.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence [1 of 4], 1991 -- 1992; UA147.002.001.00015 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [2 of 4], 1990 -- 1991; UA147.002.001.00016 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [3 of 4], 1990 -- 1991; UA147.002.001.00017 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [4 of 4], 1990; UA147.002.001.00018 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [Binder, 1 of 4], 1993 -- 1998; UA147.002.001.00019 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [Binder, 2 of 4], 1992 -- 1993; UA147.002.001.00020 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [Binder, 3 of 4], 1990 -- 1992; UA147.002.001.00021 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence [Binder, 4 of 4], 1989 -- 1990; UA147.002.001.00022 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
- Meeting files, 1989 -- 1995; UA147.003; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series consists of meeting agendas and minutes from meetings of the TDC directors, executive board and the full Corporation.
  - Minutes-agendas-working papers, April, May, June, July [Minutes-agenda-working papers, 1 of 5], 1990; UA147.003.001.00023 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Minutes-agendas-etc., Dec. 89, Jan 90, Feb 90 [Minutes-agenda-working papers, 2 of 5], 1989 -- 1990; UA147.003.001.00024 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Minutes-agendas-etc., Aug, Sept, and Oct [Minutes-agenda-working papers, 3 of 5], 1989; UA147.003.001.00025 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Minutes-agendas-etc., June and July [Minutes-agenda-working papers, 4 of 5], 1989; UA147.003.001.00026 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - TUDC [Minutes-agenda-working papers, 5 of 5], 1989 -- 1991; UA147.003.001.00027 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Minutes and agendas, Oct., Nov., and Dec. 90 and Feb. 91, 1990 -- 1991; UA147.003.001.00028 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers and directors meeting agenda material, June 5, 1991; UA147.003.001.00029 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - August 6, 1991 meeting, UA147.003.001.00030 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Weekly meetings [August 12], 1991; UA147.003.001.00031 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Off. and Dir. Meet. Oct. 3, 1991; UA147.003.001.00032 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Meeting November 4, 1991; UA147.003.001.00033 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Meeting December 2, 1991; UA147.003.001.00034 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Meeting Feb. 3, 1992; UA147.003.001.00035 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Dir. and off. Feb 6, 1992; UA147.003.001.00036 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Directors and officers meeting - September 29, 1992; UA147.003.001.00037 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers meeting on October 5, 1992; UA147.003.001.00038 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting November 2, 1992; UA147.003.001.00039 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting on January 5, 1993; UA147.003.001.00040 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting February 2, 1993; UA147.003.001.00041 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting March 1, 1993; UA147.003.001.00042 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting April 5, 1993; UA147.003.001.00043 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting May 3, 1993; UA147.003.001.00044 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting June 7, 1993; UA147.003.001.00045 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting August 4, 1993; UA147.003.001.00047 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Directors and officers meeting - August 9, 1993; UA147.003.001.00048 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting September 7, 1993; UA147.003.001.00049 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting October 4, 1993; UA147.003.001.00050 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting November 1, 1993; UA147.003.001.00051 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting December 6, 1993; UA147.003.001.00052 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting January 3, 1994; UA147.003.001.00053 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting February 7, 1994; UA147.003.001.00054 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting March 7, 1994; UA147.003.001.00055 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting April 4, 1994; UA147.003.001.00056 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting May 2, 1994; UA147.003.001.00057 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting July 6, 1994; UA147.003.001.00058 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting September 7, 1994; UA147.003.001.00059 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Directors' and officers' meeting - October 3, 1994; UA147.003.001.00060 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting November 7, 1994; UA147.003.001.00061 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting December 5, 1994; UA147.003.001.00062 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting February 6, 1995; UA147.003.001.00063 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting March 6, 1995; UA147.003.001.00064 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting April 3, 1995; UA147.003.001.00065 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting May 3, 1995; UA147.003.001.00066 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting June 7, 1995; UA147.003.001.00067 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Officers' meeting September 11, 1995; UA147.003.001.00068 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - Directors' and officers' meeting, 1995; UA147.003.001.00069 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - TUDC Minutes Book 6/7/89- [Binder 1 of 5 Front pocket], 1992; UA147.003.001.00070 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - TUDC Minutes Book 6/7/89- [Binder 2 of 5], 1992 -- 1995; UA147.003.001.00071 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - TUDC Minutes Book 6/7/89- [Binder 3 of 5], 1990 -- 1991; UA147.003.001.00072 (Box UA147 Shared 1)
  - TUDC Minutes book 6/7/89- [Binder 4 of 5], 1990; UA147.003.002.00001 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - TUDC Minutes book 6/7/89- [Binder 5 of 5], 1990; UA147.003.002.00002 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
- Project files, 1989 -- 1995; UA147.004; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series consists of subject files related to TDC projects, primarily the construction of a skyscraper on top of South Station in Boston.
  - [TUDC Air Rights, 1 of 3 (Binder-front pocket)], 1992; UA147.004.002.00003 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - [TUDC Air Rights, 2 of 3 (Binder)], 1990 -- 1992; UA147.004.002.00004 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - [TUDC Air Rights, 3 of 3 (Binder-back cover)], 1990 -- 1992; UA147.004.002.00005 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - BRA designation [Air Rights 1 of 3], 1990 -- 1991; UA147.004.002.00006 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Air rights [Air Rights 2 of 3], 1990 -- 1991; UA147.004.002.00007 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Air rights [Air Rights 3 of 3], 1990 -- 1991; UA147.004.002.00008 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Center for the Study of Drug Development, 1991; UA147.004.002.00009 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - International research center [1 of 2], 1991; UA147.004.002.00010 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - International research center brochures [International research center 2 of 2], 1991; UA147.004.002.00011 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Legal proposals for TUDC [1 of 2], 1991; UA147.004.002.00012 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Legal proposals for TUDC [2 of 2], 1991; UA147.004.002.00013 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Management advisory comm., 1990; UA147.004.002.00014 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Photographs [Media Information 1 of 2], 1990; UA147.004.002.00015 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - [Media Information 2 of 2], 1989 -- 1991; UA147.004.002.00016 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Hill and Knowlton communications proposal [Miscellaneous 1 of 5], 1991; UA147.004.002.00017 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Equity offers [Miscellaneous 2 of 5], 1991; UA147.004.002.00018 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Budget file [Miscellaneous 3 of 5], 1990; UA147.004.002.00019 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Miscellaneous 1 of 2 [Miscellaneous 4 of 5], 1990; UA147.004.002.00020 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Miscellaneous 2 of 2 [Miscellaneous 5 of 5], 1990; UA147.004.002.00021 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Potential development partners, 1990; UA147.004.002.00022 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Problems with RFP, 1990; UA147.004.002.00023 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Proposed zoning legislation, 1989 -- 1990; UA147.004.002.00024 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Response to RFP, 1990; UA147.004.002.00025 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - RFQ and RFP process, 1989; UA147.004.002.00026 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - RFP work plans [1 of 2], 1990; UA147.004.002.00027 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - RFP information and memors [RFP work plans 2 of 2], 1990; UA147.004.002.00028 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Revised concept, 1990; UA147.004.002.00029 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Brown Rudnick-synopsis and legal issues [Separate individual important documents 1 of 4], 1990; UA147.004.002.00030 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Nutter McClellan presentation [Separate individual important documents 2 of 4], 1990; UA147.004.002.00031 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Joint venture proposal Perini Land and Development Company [Separate individual important documents 3 of 4], 1990; UA147.004.002.00032 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Section 30 B Mass. Gen. Laws [Separate individual important documents 4 of 4], 1990; UA147.004.002.00033 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - South Station Technopolis Office/Biomedical Research Center, 1993; UA147.004.002.00034 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Tufts International Research Center, Volume One, The Development Program, 1990; UA147.004.002.00035 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Tufts International Research Center, Volume Two, The Development Team, 1990; UA147.004.002.00036 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - Tufts International Research Center, Volume Three, The Development Schedule and Financials, 1990; UA147.004.002.00037 (Box UA147 Shared 2)
  - TUDC, 1995; UA147.004.002.00038 (Box UA147 Shared 2)